# 大家好 那個母狗搬了一個窩 它搬到那裡面去啦
Hi everyone! The dog mom has moved her den, to there inside.
# 那小狗都好大啦 都那麼大啦 看一下
The puppies are really big now, that big now. Let's take a look.
# 這裡都是
Here is always,
# 好多刺 不好進
very spiky. It's hard to get in.
# 你看 現在狗都那麼大啦 怎麼那麼兇這隻
Look! The puppies are that big now. Why is this one so fierce?
# 那麼小 很可愛的哦
So small. It's really cute, you know.
# 長大了就不可愛了
But they're no longer cute when they grow up.
# 全部都丟裡面
All are left here.
# 放這裡它自己會回去
I put it here. It's gonna go back on its own.
# 再過 再過幾天我們就可以 搞點粥給它吃
After, after a couple of days, we can start giving them some congee.
# 搞點粥給它吃它長的很快的
With some congee, they're gonna grow really fast.
# 半個月後
A fortnight later
# 大家好 那個小狗好大了哦 把它抓出來
Hi everyone! The puppies are really big now. Let me catch them out,
# 在這個大廳裡面
and put them into the living room here.
# 給它點東西吃
I'll give them food.
# 它現在會吃東西啦
They can eat now.
# 就在那裡面
They're right there inside.
# 我把它 放在這籮筐上
I'm gonna, put them into this basket.
# 狗狗狗狗狗
Puppies, puppies, puppies!
# 過去 把它抓出來才行
I gotta, go there and catch them.
# 現在 不配合
Now they're, not listing to me.
# 狗狗狗狗狗
Puppies, puppies, puppies!
# 狗狗
Puppies!
# 一隻小黃狗
A brown puppy
# 先把這小黃狗先搬到這邊去
Let me take this brown puppy to this side first.
# 你看
Look!
# 你看 它肚子餓啦
Look! It's hungry.
# 我搞了一點那個
I've fetched some, you know,
# 剩飯跟那個湯給它吃一下
left over, and some, some soup for it.
# 吃啊 慢慢吃 還有其它的我再把它們抓出來
Just eat. Take your time. There are other puppies. I'm gonna catch them out.
# 抓了這幾條
So I've caught these puppies.
# 還有沒抓到
There are some more.
# 它不肯出來
They don't wanna come.
# 把這幾條先帶過去先
I take these puppies there first.
# 快點吃哦
C'mon! Eat!
# 你看 這小狗 都長那麼大啦
Look! These puppies, they are all that big now.
# 留點飯給它們吃
I've left some rice for them.
# 我是我們吃 吃剩下的剩飯
This is the left, leftover from our meals.
# 快點吃啊
C'mon! Eat!
# 12345678 8條
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight. Eight puppies
# 你看
Look!
# 好壯啊 它
So strong, it looks.
# 在這裡玩多好哇 天天都鑽到那個樹底下去
It's so much fun here, isn't it? But they're squeezing into the den under the trees every day.
# 讓我們抓都抓不到它
We can't even catch you,
# 看也看不到
nor see you.
# 一個多月不見 現在長那麼大啦
After more than a month, they've grown so much now.
# 吃飽沒有
Have you guys eaten enough?
# 吃飽喝足來哦
You've had enough, right?
# 你們就不吃了嗎
So you've finished?
# 它們吃的好飽啊 看到沒有 肚子都供[SIC]起來啦
They've eaten so much. See? The belly is pushing out.
# 這個也是
And this one too
# 呵呵 好不好吃
Hehe. Did you enjoy the food?
# 剛剛我叫你出來你就不出 躲在那裡面
Just now you didn't come out even I asked you to. You were hiding there inside.
# 硬把它扯出來
I needed to drag it out.
# 快 吃奶奶啦
C'mon! Milk time now.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 再給它 再搞點給它們吃的
Let me give them, give them some more food.
# 還沒吃飽
They haven't eaten enough.